( Emily ) Ever seen a shooting star ?
Sure .
You ?
You know what you 're supposed to do , right ?
What do you mean , make a wish ?
So , if you saw one right now , what would you wish for ?
Well , that 's a secret .
What about you ?
To know why it took you so long .
All freshman year Biology ,
we sat next to each other , you don 't even remember .
No , hey , I remember .
Okay ?
How about the next year we had two classes , do you remember which ?
- Never even noticed . - Oh , hey , that 's not true .
So this is it .
We 're about to graduate and now you ask me out .
Now you want to start something ?
Hey , I 'm sorry .
Okay ? You 've got to forgive me .
Sometimes , you just ...
You don 't see what 's right in front of you .
Yeah , you don 't see .
Okay , so what ? You 're going to leave ?
You ditch me , we 'll be even ?
Look , I can 't change the past , Emily .
All I know is about tonight .
And tonight you are my wish .
( lock clicks )
( keys jingling )
( sighing )
So , uh ...
Make yourself
you know .
- It 's nice , your place . - Thanks .
Whoa .
Is it that late already ?
- I thought your parents were away . - Oh . They are .
I just , um ...
I guess I lost track of time here .
Uh ... Can I get you something to drink ?
- Sure . - Yeah ? Okay .
- I 'll be right back , okay ? - Okay .
Hey .
I wanna show you something .
What ?
( grunts )
- Thank you . - There you go .
To secrets .
- Secrets ? - And sharing them .
Have you ever seen something so scary
that you had to show to someone else ?
Um ...
I mean , like , you know , a movie or something .
Well ...
Okay , I 've got the scariest freakin ' movie you 'll ever see .
- now ... - ( clears throat )
A buddy of mine actually turned me on to it .
And , uh , he made me a copy .
So ... I did one for you .
You brought me here to watch a video ?
Well , two minutes . Okay ?
Two minutes and it 'll all be over .
It 's totally underground stuff .
I thought we were gonna just ...
No , we will . We will .
You just gotta see this . I 'm telling you , it 's ...
- How about after we ... ? - No , you need to watch it now .
Okay ?
So , um ...
Just put it in the VCR , and press play ,
and as soon as it 's over , I 'll be right back in .
- Wait , back ? - Yeah , I 've seen it .
( stammers ) It 's scarier by yourself .
Look , my buddy did this to me . Okay ?
This would really mean something to me , Emily .
You know , like ...
Like we 're together .
What 's so scary about it ?
You 'll see .
( breathing heavily )
Play it . Just play the thing .
Come on , I got two minutes here , please .
( TV static )
( panting nervously )
Emily , play the goddamn tape !
( humming , hissing )
( rumbling )
( whining , gurgling )
( sighs )
( whining continues )
( phone ringing )
( high-pitched electronic whine )
( ringing continues )
- Hello ? - ( man ) Tick tock , time 's up .
What went down , man ? You got someone to watch it ?
( sighing ) Yeah , yeah . Yeah , man .
Some stupid chick from my school .
( man ) Good . I was afraid you didn 't believe me , man .
You don 't show somebody else a copy within a week ,
I swear you 're dead .
This is freaky stuff , man , freaky stuff .
My cousin , he showed it to his friend ,
his friend didn 't believe him ,
- ( water gurgling ) - he was dead in a week .
( man ) Jake ?
Jake ?
Are you there , man ?
- Don 't play around with me . - ( hangs up phone )
Emily ?
Emily !
Emily , what the hell did you do ?
I played it , I just didn 't look .
( screaming )
( humming )
( TV static , hissing )
( woman chuckling )
( Rachel ) Come on , Aidan , let 's go home .
It was the right choice . No question .
Aidan , dinner 's ready .
( sighs ) Damn .
Aidan !
Okay , now , before you say anything , I followed the recipe this time .
So just ' cause it doesn 't look like the one in the magazine ,
doesn 't mean to say it won 't taste good .
Those are great , honey . Got a really good eye .
He 'd be proud of you .
Thanks , Rachel .
You know , it wouldn 't kill you to call me " mom " now and again .
" Ma . " " Mommy . "
Something besides " Rachel . "
Yeah , I like " Rachel . "
Well , " mom " has its charms too , you know ?
But " Rachel " is more your personality .
Really ?
Well , Rachel declares dinnertime .
It 's working out great , don 't you think ?
All of this space and fresh air .
We have a yard .
It 's really great .
Listen , honey
we didn 't do anything wrong .
We did what anyone would do .
We started over .
( man on TV speaking indistinctly )
( knocking )
Yeah .
- Hey . - Hey .
Uh , you know how they can tell you used to work at a real newspaper ?
You 're the only one who closes your door .
Habit .
Uh , I wanted to talk to you about my editorial .
Those changes okay ?
Well , I asked you to copy edit it and you rewrote it .
Well , just the part about the bond measure .
That was the whole thing .
It 's the bridge that would get the money , not the riverfront .
Yeah , uh ...
It 's kind of a tradition here that I write the lead editorial .
- It is my paper . - Of course .
- I own it and I hired you . - Right .
Uh-huh .
I just wouldn 't want to see us print an opinion that was ...
What 's the word ?
Wrong ?
Good a reason as any .
Rachel .
Um ...
You know , a big news day in Astoria
is a school board meeting , a car wreck and a cat in a tree .
That 's big news .
You sure this is the job you 're looking for ?
Well , I 'm around for my son more .
In Seattle , I wasn 't .
Good a reason as any .
Um , I 'm glad to see you 're settling in . I like the ...
Hey , Max , while you 're here ,
have you given any thought to that piece for tomorrow ?
You know what ? Don 't you worry about it .
Sorry .
( man on radio ) It 's 442 Ridgecrest .
( woman on radio ) Repeat that . It 's what ?
( man ) Ridgecrest . Ridgecrest !
I 've talked to the medical examiner . They 're on their way .
( man # 2 ) Squad 19 to respond .
( woman ) Squad 19 , can we keep this channel clear , please ?
- The police found a body . - Possible homicide .
- Please , we should be so lucky . - What are they saying ?
" High school student , male , 17 . Address , 442 Ridgecrest .
Found the house partially flooded , and a girlfriend hiding in the basement . "
Suspect or witness , they don 't know .
The guy was dead right in front of the TV .
( man ) They keep on talking about his face .
What about his face ?
( woman on radio ) All emergency units , area Astoria ,
switch to Tack Five .
( indistinct radio chatter )
( car approaching )
( woman ) Detective .
Detective , you have a minute ? Was it homicide or wasn 't it ?
You know how he died , don 't you ?
( man ) I just have a few last questions .
If you could walk me through it again .
( woman ) It 's just horrible . So young .
( gasping )
( breathing nervously )
( crying ) No .
No , please , not here .
( men chattering )
( whimpering )
( girl ) I found you .
( hissing )
( grunting , panting )
We only made one copy .
Oh , God .
- Excuse me , sir . - Hold on .
- Yeah ? - Hi .
I 'm Rachel Keller from the Daily Astorian .
We 'll make a statement .
I need to know about the girl .
She hasn 't said a word , has she ?
You 're welcome to wait . Excuse me .
( man ) Watch your step . Have a seat here , okay ?
Have a seat . I just want you to relax for me .
You can 't keep her here . She 's scared .
- ( man # 1 ) Focus on the walls . - ( man # 2 ) We wanna take her .
- ( woman ) She 'll talk to us . - ( man # 1 ) I understand .
I 'm just gonna ask a few questions in private .
It 'll just take a minute . Please .
- Be right back , Emily . - Thank you . Thank you .
All right . Give me his number . Yeah . All right .
Emily .
Emily , listen to me . I know what happened .
I know .
Now , you have to tell me . The tape .
Did you watch it ?
Do you know who else has watched it ?
Has anyone else watched it ?
No .
Then where is it ?
Hey , you . Get away from her . Ray .
Emily , talk to me .
( man ) I want her out of here . Now .
You can tell me , Emily .
( sighs )
( hissing )
( whining )
No .
( panting )
Not here , Samara . Not here .
( whining , groaning )
( hissing , rumbling )
( water gurgling )
Rachel ?
( breathing heavily )
( electronic whirring )
( breathing nervously )
( water gurgling )
Rachel !
( straining )
( muffled ) Rachel ! Rachel !
Rachel ! Rachel !
Honey , what is it ?
- What 's wrong ? Huh ? - ( panting )
Look at me . Shh .
- Okay ? What is it ? - I had a nightmare .
That 's all right . We all have them .
Oh , God , you 're soaked . And you 're freezing .
Let 's get you out of these clothes . Come on .
Aidan ?
What happened in your nightmare ?
I woke up and you weren 't here .
You weren 't here .
I 'm here now , honey . I 'm right here , okay ?
Listen .
All you have to do is call my name and I 'll follow your voice .
Okay ?
Even if I have to come right down into that nightmare with you .
So tell me what happened .
Hmm ?
I don 't remember .
You don 't remember ?
( rumbling )
- ( Rachel muffled ) Aidan . - ( kids laughing )
( Rachel ) Aidan .
Aidan .
Honey . You heard me ?
I 've been calling your name .
I 'm ... sorry .
- You ready to go ? - Mm-hmm . Yeah .
Okay .
( people chattering )
( Rachel ) So we 'll just swing by and see what they have , okay ?
And you can keep a watch on the backyard stuff . How 's that ?
Look at all this stuff . Who do you think buys this crap ?
Rachel . Hi .
- Hi . - You guys , come here .
Here 's the new neighbor I was telling you about .
Rachel Keller .
She works for the Daily Astoria .
Oh , Rachel , meet Meg Lowry and Audrey Flint
- Hello . - Hello .
So ... Looking for stuff to fill up that new house , huh ?
You should see what Rachel is doing with it .
She 's doing with it , a kind of , um
a country loft look , right ?
Did they replace that orange linoleum
in the back bathroom there before you moved in ?
( woman ) Oh , you are so bad .
( all laughing )
You know , you really should get here early , Rachel ,
because the good stuff is gone by noon .
I 'm sorry , just a sec .
Whatever I say , walk and keep walking , all right ?
- I 'm sorry . I forgot your names . - Oh , Meg and Audrey .
Aidan , stay with me , honey .
( woman chuckling ) Kids .
Yeah , well , there 's a reason God made them so cute .
Huh ?
( all ) So we don 't kill them .
- I really should ... - Oh , we know .
Go ahead , we 're around . We 'll run into you .
- It 's good to meet you . - You , too .
Good luck with everything .
- Take care now . - Goodbye .
Aidan ?
Thank you , I owe you one .
Don 't you want friends ?
Those aren 't friends , honey . They 're the secret police .
You still cold ?
What 's wrong , honey ? You all right ?
Mm-hmm .
- I 'm gonna take a look around . - All right .
Stay close .
( chattering continues )
Would you like a marble , ma 'am ?
( chattering fades out )
Hello , young man .
Have you received your free Lucky marble today ?
( Max ) I wouldn 't , if I were you .
I heard they don 't even make the machines anymore .
Fine with me .
( sighs ) Well , I guess it 's proof there 's not a lot to do around here .
Not much happens .
Although , the past three months we had a couple of interesting events ,
haven 't we ?
A couple ?
What ? Something happened before the murder ?
Yeah , well , you came here . That was interesting .
Is that a line , Max ?
More of a question .
Why would you choose to live here ?
No one would choose to live in a place like this .
It 's ... quiet .
Well , I got to tell you , I think it 's too quiet .
I can 't sleep , I miss noise . I miss garbage trucks .
I lived in New York for ten years .
Four years at Columbia , then the Daily News , for me
that place is home .
- I thought you were born here . - Oh , yeah , I was .
I moved back .
- It 's not that tragic . - I 'm just surprised , that 's all .
Found out my parents weren 't well ,
so I came back to help out for a while .
I 'm still here .
Are they still ...
No . I got the house , I got the paper .
And I got the 20 employees in the town
I swore I would never come back to .
- Home sick . - Yeah .
- Yeah . Terminal case . - I recognize the symptoms .
- Hey , Max , how are you ? - Good , Dale .
Who 's the little cutie ?
Uh ... New editor , Dale . Co-worker , colleague .
Whatever you say .
This place will grow on you , Rachel .
Are you ready ? You guys all ready to go ?
On your mark , get set ,
go !
( Max ) Love to meet him . You should bring him by sometime .
- ( Rachel ) I will . - Paper 's the only family I have .
- So , I try to treat it like one . - I can see that .
Whenever you want to tell me , feel free to .
- Tell you what ? - Why here ?
Like I said , it 's quiet .
Okay .
You don 't have kids , do you , Max ?
Everything I do is for my son .
Everything .
- I should ... - Sure .
I really would like to meet him .
See if he 's anything like you .
Man , that was genius .
( Rachel ) Aidan ?
( flushing )
Aidan .
( faucet squeaking )
( rumbling )
Aidan ?
( man ) You gotta wait for the whistle .
Aidan .
( faucet squeaking )
( buzzing )
( rumbling )
( shutter clicking )
Aidan ! Aidan !
( carnival music playing )
Are you in there ?
Aidan ?
Why didn 't you answer me , honey ? What are you ... ?
Jesus .
Jesus , you 're freezing , honey . What 's going on ? Are you sick ?
Talk to me , honey .
Talk to me . What 's going on ?
- What is it ? - I 'm cold .
Oh .
It 's okay . It 's okay .
Honey , when did this start ?
Was it last night ,
or this morning ?
I don 't remember .
I know you don 't like me prying , but this is important , okay ?
Was it your nightmare ?
I really don 't remember , Rachel .
I need you to try .
You 're sick , all right ?
And we need to know what started it .
Aidan .
Was she in your nightmare ?
Rachel !
( screeching )
( grunting )
( gasps )
( Aidan panting ) Don 't stop .
Don 't stop .
- Go ! Drive ! Drive ! - What 's the matter , honey ?
Just don 't stop the car !
( grunting , snorting )
( Rachel ) Get down !
( grunting )
( engine revving )
( shrieking )
- Why did you say ... - Rachel !
( grunting )
( both panting )
" Don 't stop . "
You said , " Don 't stop . "
( deer grunting )
Oh , my God .
( grunting )
( snorts )
( deer bellowing )
Don 't stop .
( beeping )
Okay . Let 's see .
That 's impossible .
Rachel
what 's happening ?
( sighing )
Yeah , hi , um ...
My son is very sick
and I 'd like to talk to someone who ...
Right .
Well , it 's his temperature .
It 's ... It 's five degrees low .
( static )
Okay .
( water running )
Keep him warm .
( rumbling )
( rattling )
- ( gasps ) Oh , my God . - ( glass shatters )
Oh , my God .
( alarm beeping )
( screams )
Aidan ?
Honey .
- ( wind howling ) - Honey , this shouldn 't be open .
God .
( scratching )
Aidan , let 's go . Get out of bed .
Aidan , what are you doing over there ?
Get back in bed right now .
I saw something .
- ( crackling ) - ( rumbling )
Aidan ...
Move ! Get away . Get away from there .
Honey , let 's go . Come on .
- ( Aidan ) I saw it . - ( Rachel breathing heavily )
- I saw it in my head . - Let 's go .
( fog horn blaring )
( people chattering )
Oh , Ms. Keller ...
- About my story . I ... - Not now .
Now , listen , sweetie . Last night I found a tape .
It was one of hers .
And I made it so we 'd never have to see it again .
But if she knows that ,
what I did might make her wanna hurt us .
Am I right ?
Do you know something , honey ?
Look , if you know why she 's here , you have to tell me .
Aidan
is she here to hurt you ?
Honey .
( whispering ) She can hear us .
She hears everything .
Except when we sleep .
She can 't hear us when we sleep ?
What does that mean ?
We have to sleep .
( knocking )
( Max ) Rachel , may I come in , please ?
Yeah .
What happened to your car ?
Your car . Apparently it 's wrecked .
- Are you guys okay ? - Yeah . We got hit .
( Max ) And no one 's hurt ?
That 's good .
Aidan , right ? Hi , I 'm Max .
- Is he all right ? - He 's sick .
How sick ?
Max , I need your help .
Here .
I 'll get some more blankets .
The house is yours if there 's anything you need at all .
( Rachel ) Okay . Thanks .
- Here . - Thank you .
Shouldn 't he be at a hospital ?
No , he 's fine .
The bath ?
Just down the hall . I 'll get it started .
Honey .
I 'm gonna go home and get some of our things .
Then we 'll leave here and never come back , okay ?
( Rachel ) Let 's get you warmed up .
Not the best water pressure , but it works .
It 's good , thanks .
I don 't know why we lost power . The block seemed fine .
I have plenty of candles in case the problem spreads .
Let 's go ahead and get in . Get you warmed up .
Max , I just need to go back to my house ,
get a few things , some medicine .
Do you mind if you could ... ?
- I 'll watch him . Of course . - Okay , thanks .
Honey , go ahead and get in . Let 's go . Let 's go .
We need to raise your temperature . Now , let 's get in .
Aidan , what 's wrong ? It 's just water .
We need to raise your temperature ...
I don 't want to , Rachel .
Do you want me to get in with you ?
Let 's go then . Aidan . Come on , let 's go .
That 's it .
Come on , honey . Let 's go . Let 's go .
That 's it . That 's it .
That 's better , right ?
See ? It 's nice and warm .
It 's okay . Just relax .
( wailing )
( water pouring )
( phone ringing )
( Max ) Hello ?
Officer Ray . How you doing ?
Yeah , good , good . All right , what do you got for me ?
Mm-hmm . Right . Yeah . Yeah .
Yeah , well , that all sounds like page 26 .
You don 't have any headlines ?
No ?
Well , business is business .
Yeah . No , no , I 'm good . Real good .
Could you do me a little favor while I 've got you ?
Could you look into your accident reports
and see if there was an accident with a woman and her son ?
" K " for Keller .
No , no , I 'm just trying to get a story straight .
( door squeaks shut )
Ray ?
Ray , let me call you right back . Okay .
( knocking )
Everything okay in there ?
Uh , Aidan , could you , uh , unlock the door , please ?
( knocking ) Aidan , can you hear me ?
Aidan , please , unlock the door !
Aidan , open the door !
Aidan . Aidan . Aidan !
He 's in the bath . It was open a second ago .
- Aidan , open the door ! - I 'll get something to break it .
Aidan , open up the door . I 'm right here .
Honey , can you hear me ? Please .
You need to open up the door .
Aidan !
Aidan .
Oh , my God .
Aidan !
Aidan .
Please , honey , open the ...
Oh , my God .
( squeaking )
Oh !
Aidan .
Aidan . Aidan .
Look at me .
Aidan , look at me . Look at me .
( coughing )
- Mommy ! - ( gasps )
( shrieks )
( Max ) Rachel , no !
( coughing )
Baby . Oh .
Oh , my God . Baby , I 'm sorry .
It wasn 't him . It wasn 't him .
I was just trying to help .
Okay , Rachel , let 's just get him out of there .
Why is she doing this to me ?
I 'm here now , baby .
- Why is she doing this to me ? - It 's okay , Aidan .
We 're gonna get you to a hospital .
No !
- They can 't do anything . - ( coughing )
You asked for my help , you 're gonna get my help .
He gets to a hospital , Rachel . Now .
( crying )
( woman on PA speaking indistinctly )
( woman on TV ) All right , everyone ,
We 're back , continuing with our outdoor theme .
I hope that you 're enjoying the show so far .
Summer finally seems to be here
and I know with Memorial approaching ,
it 's the official kick off of summer .
One thing we love to do throughout the summer months
is spend time outdoors with our friends and family .
We 've offered you what I think
is one of the most affordable sets ...
( static )
( banging )
... is really very , very pretty .
Sorry , I 'm starting to perspire a little .
But it 's hot here already in Florida .
( nurse 1 ) I wonder how long it 's been going on .
What are those bruises doing there ?
If you wanted to make those drinks that require an umbrella ,
you could make it in bulk , if you will .
Put it in the pitcher and away you go .
This is a really great set
because you 're getting them with hibiscuses all over ,
it 's a hibiscus pitcher , it 's a 30 ounce pitcher , so ...
( man ) ... his core temperature .
He was at 90 degrees when he came in .
- He wasn 't outside overnight ? - No . He was at home with me .
A body doesn 't develop severe hypothermia on its own .
Whatever the cause , he 's fighting it .
Seems like he 's stabilizing .
- And he 's just sleeping now ? - Right .
And having some kind of dream .
What 's the story , Rachel ?
They stabilized his temperature .
I mean the story with you and Aidan .
You seem awfully hard on him .
Look , I know it 's a stressful time for you .
Moving . It 's a whole new life .
Maybe you should tell me .
All I ever tried to do for him was the right thing ,
and it only ever made things worse .
Then it wasn 't the right thing , was it ?
( Rachel ) What do you see ?
Well , it 's Aidan .
- Is that a girl there ? - Why is she in the picture ?
- Why ? How would I know ? - Why is she in all of them ?
Her name 's Samara .
She was murdered by her mother .
Left to die at the bottom of a well .
- Wait , she 's ... She 's who ? - She didn 't die .
At least , not her ghost . I kept it alive for Aidan .
I let it out , it spread and then we ran .
- What are you talking about ? - I know this sounds crazy ,
but she 's here now . She 's found us .
And I thought it was just to hurt Aidan ,
but it 's more than that . She wants to be him .
And she wants to live for real this time .
You tell me , who can help me ?
Who ?
I 'm sure there 's a rational ...
You take his picture and tell me why she 's in it .
- Rachel . - You take his picture .
It 's proof that he 's what ? He 's got a ghost inside him ?
No . The proof is what will happen .
( Rachel ) Aidan , you said Samara couldn 't hear us when we sleep .
Well , you 're sleeping now .
Tell me how to stop her , honey .
Tell me how to help you .
Just tell me , I 'll do anything , I swear .
( gasping )
- ( woman singing softly ) - ( low rumbling )
( electronic whirring )
( woman singing softly )
( woman screaming )
( high-pitched scream )
( grinding )
( breathing heavily )
Aidan ?
- Aidan ? - ( Dr. Temple ) Ms. Keller ?
Hello , I 'm Dr. Emma Temple .
I 'm a consulting physician at County Child Services .
Well , I was hoping to speak with Aidan when he wakes up .
Is everything all right in here ?
Yeah . It 's fine . Thank you .
( Dr. Temple ) I was hoping to speak with you as well .
It 's Rachel , isn 't it ? Yeah , about his situation .
( Rachel ) I 'm sorry , what kind of doctor did you say you were again ?
I 'm a psychiatrist .
Yeah . I spoke with a Dr. , um
Koji in Seattle . Aidan 's doctor .
Look , if we could maybe talk later .
Right . Um , Dr. Koji mentioned that you dealt with some PPD
when Aidan was born .
Postpartum depression .
That was the first month . That 's all .
I understand . It 's very common .
I mean , a lot of women have trouble adapting to the stresses of motherhood .
What does this have to do with what 's going on with my son right now ?
Have you been under stress lately ?
Have you ever found that you were
unable to experience love for Aidan ?
- What ? - Have you hurt him ,
however unintentionally ?
Have you left him alone ? Abandoned him ?
I 'd like to be with my son , please , if you don 't mind .
Yeah , of course .
I 'm sorry , Rachel .
( beeping )
Until we can talk further ,
I cannot let you be alone with him .
I 'm his mother .
There are bruises on his body .
He was hypothermic and very near death .
That is not because of me .
( Dr. Temple ) He 's gonna be all right , Rachel . He will .
But you need to leave .
Now , please .
( whispering ) You can 't have him , Samara .
You 're going back to where you came from .
We 'll talk in here .
It really will help .
Sharing one 's troubles never hurt anybody .
- Now , are you a coffee drinker ? - Black .
Yeah , I imagined so .
( woman on PA ) Dr. Forrest , dial 118 , please .
Dr. Forrest , please dial 118 .
So , let 's call the doctor in Seattle .
I want to know just how bad her postpartum got .
- Yes . - Thank you .
The mother is missing .
I want a watch on this room .
She returns , she is not allowed in .
Okay , Dr. Temple .
All I wanna know is what her history was before the Morgans .
I 'm sorry , but the privacy laws still apply .
Well , was she really adopted ? Can you at least tell me that much ?
Was their story true ?
Samara Morgan was adopted , yes .
But you won 't tell me from who ?
- I 'd lose my job if I did . - ( sighing ) Look , ma 'am ,
my son has a medical condition that his doctors don 't even understand .
This little girl had the same condition .
Now , if I knew what caused that , it could save his life .
( woman ) All I can say is you should speak to the Morgans .
They 're dead . They both killed themselves .
Whoa ! Look out . Early birds .
Marty Savide , Stevens Northwest Realty .
- Hi . - Uh , come in .
I thought I put 12 : 30 on the ad . For the open house .
- How 'd you get around the gate ? - Well , I just ...
Ah ! Who cares ? Come on .
Make me an offer over asking and it 's yours .
Okay , then , don 't mind me .
My first try with these things , took off flying .
( chuckling )
There we go .
What do you think ?
Um , a little color will really turn the place around .
It 's got a wonderful history .
Working horse ranch . How about that ?
And there 's even this cute little tree house thing way up in the barn .
Um , is the place being sold unfurnished or ... ?
The previous owners didn 't leave anything behind ?
Well , there were some things that were left , after they
moved .
We 're storing all that in the basement .
There 's a basement ?
Uh ... Well , you betcha . No extra charge .
Right this way .
( low rumbling )
( Savide ) Uh , if you don 't mind , I 'm the welcome wagon .
Gotta open up the gate for everyone else .
So please , just make yourself at home .
Do you know what happened to them ? The previous owners ?
I believe they bought a condo in Phoenix .
Really ?
( music box music plays )
( woman singing softly )
Her mother .
( gasps )
( static )
( clicking )
Oh , my .
You 're awake .
I 'll take it from here .
Hello , Aidan , I 'm Dr. Temple .
How are you feeling ?
Aidan ?
You know , I 'd really like to help you .
Can you tell me how you 're feeling ?
Where 's my mommy ?
Well , she 'll be here soon . She 's on her way .
I want Mommy .
Yeah , I know you do .
Your mommy wants to be with you too .
So where is she ?
She went home .
She didn 't think that you were gonna wake up so soon .
I wanna go home too .
Well , you will .
We just have to ... We just have to get you ...
You 're freezing .
I wanna go home to Mommy .
Well , we need to talk about her .
Can you tell me about Mommy a little bit ?
She loves me .
I know that she does .
She went looking for me . She tried to find me .
It means she loves me .
I don 't understand .
Can I go home now ?
No , honey , you 're not well enough .
Can I go home ?
No .
I 'm sorry .
Then I have to show you something .
( ominous music playing )
It won 't stop .
( exhales )
Hi , I 'm Sister Diane , how can I help you ?
Yeah , I need to know about a child who was born here .
Is there anyone that can talk to me
who 's been here more than 30 years ?
Please , come in .
( indistinct chatter )
( children talking indistinctly )
I remember this , yes .
A young girl made it .
Sixteen .
She was shy . Quite .
Beautiful .
- She stayed here ? - Yes .
- Did she have her baby here ? - Yes .
And you arranged for the adoption ?
That 's right .
Who was she ?
She was picked up wandering the streets and brought to us .
She was from some little town up in the mountains .
( drawer opens )
She said she 'd been sent away
to live with relatives in the city .
But no relatives were ever found .
Her name was Evelyn .
She came to us eight months pregnant .
- And the father ? - There was none .
Half the mothers that come to us say that .
So , what did she think got her pregnant ?
( woman ) Evelyn wasn 't well .
She had been having problems during the pregnancy :
Hallucinations , visions .
She believed some thing had come for her baby
from the waters of the world beyond this one .
I 'm sorry . Did you say water ?
Well , we all envision the afterlife differently .
For Evelyn , it 's just what she believed .
As you might imagine , she suffered severe postpartum depression .
She blamed her troubles on her child .
So she tried to kill it .
- All babies are a challenge . - ( baby cooing )
But Samara , she never cried .
Never .
Except when her mother would try to bathe her .
Then she 'd scream like it was the end of the world .
It was the screaming that woke us .
( baby screaming and crying )
- Evelyn , don 't ! - ( crying continues )
( woman ) Evelyn !
Evelyn , stop !
( baby crying )
( woman ) She was trying to drown the baby .
The baby was taken from her , of course .
Evelyn was institutionalized .
And all those pictures she 'd been collecting ,
they finally made sense .
Did she say why she did it ?
She felt she had to kill her baby to save it .
I 'm here to see a patient . Her name 's Evelyn .
- I don 't know her last name . - Evelyn ?
That 's right .
Evelyn 's expecting you .
Every few years , one of you comes to see Evelyn .
She 's like a freakin ' patron saint or something .
Got a problem with your kid , don 't you ?
( woman singing softly )
Something wrong ?
That song . I know it .
Yeah . They all do .
( keys jangling )
( door unlocking )
Hey , Evelyn .
You were right as rain . You got a visitor today .
Hope she 's some help to your troubles .
Ten minutes .
- ( scissors cutting ) - ( woman humming )
( door closes )
My name 's Rachel .
But you know that .
( continues cutting )
( Evelyn ) Some days I sort of have a feeling .
A feeling ?
This is about your child .
It 's ...
- It 's about yours . - ( cutting stops )
Samara .
They don 't dream , you know .
The dead don 't dream .
Look , something 's happened to my son .
- You have to sleep to dream . - It has to do with your daughter .
And the dead never sleep .
They wait
and watch for a way back .
But they never sleep .
- That 's why dreams are safe . - I 'm sorry , I just ...
I don 't have a lot of time . Please , I need your help .
I have to know . Can you tell me ?
Why did you try to kill your baby ?
Why ?
Because my baby told me to .
Just like yours will tell you .
And you have to do it .
- You have to send it back . - What ?
They stopped me .
- Don 't let them stop you . - What ?
Listen to the voices .
What are you talking about ?
Because it 's our fault . We did it .
Yes . We did it . Yes .
It was you . It was you ! You did it !
What did I do ?
( door unbolting )
( man ) Evelyn , that 's enough .
I love my son .
( man ) Come on . It 's all right .
I 'm sorry , ma 'am , that 's enough for today .
Let 's go .
What did I do ?
You let the dead get in .
( man ) Let 's go .
What should I do ?
Be a good mother .
Listen to your baby .
- Listen to your baby . - ( door locking )
- ( cutting resumes ) - ( humming continues )
( TV static )
( knocking ) Aidan ?
Hey .
Shouldn 't you , uh ...
Shouldn 't you be at the hospital ?
No . I 'm here waiting for my mommy .
Okay .
Well , you can 't really leave till the hospital says it 's okay .
You were very , very sick .
You 're all right now ?
The cable setup at my house ,
the TV needs to be on channel three .
She loves me . She loves me not .
- Thank you , Max . - Sure .
She loves me !
Look , Mandy !
I think I 'm gonna puke .
Why don 't you do something productive with your life ?
( indistinct sound on TV )
( man on TV ) Say , Billy , if you like fish so much ...
Your mom loves you , you know .
She loves you a lot .
You 'd tell someone if you weren 't sure about that , right ?
Like , if she 'd been hurting you somehow .
Did she ever treat you like you 're someone else ?
- I 'm not somebody else . I 'm Aidan . - Yeah , I know .
- Hey , I know . - We don 't need anyone else .
That 's right .
We don 't need you , that doctor or anyone else .
Okay ?
Okay .
What are you doing ?
I was just gonna take a picture of you .
No .
- It 'll be for your mom . - No .
Why not ? What 's wrong with taking your picture ?
I 'll tell you what 's wrong if you promise not to take it .
But that 's only if you promise .
Fine . I promise .
( clears throat )
( sighs )
So , Aidan , what 's the story ?
( man on TV ) * We 're happy when we 're sad
* We 're always feeling sad
( Rachel ) Hello ?
- ( TV ) How are you ? - Terrible .
* That 's why we 're happy when we 're sad * *
Max ?
Are you here ?
- You 're home ! - ( gasping ) Oh , God .
What are you doing here ? I thought you were at the hospital .
No . I 'm here , Mommy .
- What did you say ? - I said I 'm here .
Is Max here ?
No .
But his coat ...
He went away . You wanna watch some TV with me ?
Uh ...
( TV turns on )
I , uh , I just have to get something from the car . Okay ?
I love you , Mommy .
Max .
Max ?
( screaming )
( shuddering )
( man on TV ) Goldfish must have water in order to exist .
But goldfish hate cats .
While on the other hand , cats hate water .
( crying )
Rachel .
Are you sleeping , Rachel ?
I am . She makes me sleep all the time now .
Aidan .
Shh . Just keep sleeping , Rachel .
So she can 't hear us . It 's the only way .
You have to show her , Rachel .
Show her she can 't stay .
In you .
How ? How do I do that ?
Take me to where she 's afraid of .
- You know where she 's afraid of . - ( mouths word ) Water .
Take me there ...
- ... and kill me . - Aidan , no .
Shh . Rachel , keep sleeping .
She won 't stay if she knows you 'll kill me .
- ( Aidan ) It 's the only way . - I can 't do it . I can 't .
Then she stays .
- ( whirring ) - ( gasping ) She 's heard us .
( panting )
( TV indistinct )
Honey ?
I thought you were sleeping , Mommy .
I was , but I had a bad dream .
You must 've had a nightmare .
It 's all right . We all have them .
Will you stay with me now ?
- Stay ? - Stay for always .
Yeah . Yeah .
Alrighty . Let 's watch some TV together .
It 's kind of late , honey .
Don 't you think you should sleep ?
I never sleep .
Then let Mommy make you something .
Something wrong ? You seem sad .
No , honey , I 'm not sad .
I 'm just tired , that 's all .
Well , now you have me to protect you .
( woman singing on TV )
* You ain 't the biggest catfish in the deep blue sea * *
( Aidan ) Take me to where she 's afraid of .
You know where she 's afraid of .
You have to show her , Rachel .
Show her she can 't stay .
( Evelyn ) Listen to the voices .
You have to listen to the voices .
( echoing ) Be a good mother . Be a good mother .
Listen to your baby .
( distorted screeching )
I 'm sorry .
I 'm so sorry .
But you can 't stay .
What are you doing ? Rachel !
What are you doing ?
It 's me .
- It 's not her , Rachel . - I know , baby .
- It 's me . - Shh .
I love you . Mommy , I love you .
I know , baby .
I love you too .
But you 're not my son .
( gasping )
( panting )
( screeching )
Mommy .
Aidan .
Aidan . Aidan . Aidan .
( grunts )
Honey .
Breathe . Baby , breathe .
Please . I know it 's you , honey .
Aidan .
Aidan , please .
Rachel .
Yeah .
I 'm right here .
You 're okay .
Everything 's all right , honey .
( sighs )
You were sleeping .
You were just sleeping .
( high-pitched squeal )
( eerie whining )
No .
( water flowing )
She wants me again .
No .
Rachel , what are you doing ?
All she wants is a mother . That 's all she wants .
And she 'll keep coming till she finds one .
( Aidan ) Come on ! Come back !
Get away from her ! Rachel !
Get away from her !
You can 't have my son .
So take me .
Rachel ! No !
Rachel ! Rachel !
( crashing )
( coughing )
Samara !
Here I am , Samara .
Just like you wanted .
But you leave him alone !
You hear me ?
( electric buzzing )
( Samara ) Help me .
It 's always open .
Her only way out is always open .
( Samara muffled ) Mommy .
Mommy !
Mommy .
( high-pitched squeal )
( water bubbling )
( breathing heavily )
( panting , straining )
- Mommy ! - I 'm not your fucking mommy .
( panting )
( Aidan ) Rachel .
Rachel .
( whirring )
( Aidan ) Rachel .
Rachel .
- Can you hear me ? - I can hear you .
( Aidan ) I 'm right here .
( silence )
( Aidan ) Rachel .
Rachel !
You 're here .
- You 're here , Rachel . - Of course I 'm here .
I followed your voice .
What happened ?
It 's over , honey .
She 's not coming back .
How do you know , Rachel ?
I know .
I promise .
I love you , Mommy .
Promise me something ?
Yeah . Anything , Mom . Anything .
Just call me Rachel .
( chuckles )
At least for a while .
( whirring , hissing )